<RelativeLayout xmlns:android="http://schemas.android.com/apk/res/android"
    xmlns:tools="http://schemas.android.com/tools"
    android:layout_width="match_parent"
    android:layout_height="match_parent"
    android:background="@drawable/bg2"
    android:paddingBottom="@dimen/activity_vertical_margin"
    android:paddingLeft="@dimen/activity_horizontal_margin"
    android:paddingRight="@dimen/activity_horizontal_margin"
    android:paddingTop="@dimen/activity_vertical_margin"
    tools:context=".Computer_programming_lab" >

    <ScrollView
        android:id="@+id/scrollView1"
        android:layout_width="wrap_content"
        android:layout_height="wrap_content"
        android:layout_alignParentLeft="true"
        android:layout_alignParentRight="true"
        android:layout_alignParentTop="true" >

        <LinearLayout
            android:layout_width="match_parent"
            android:layout_height="match_parent"
            android:orientation="vertical" >

            <TextView
                android:id="@+id/textView1"
                android:layout_width="wrap_content"
                android:layout_height="wrap_content"
                android:textColor="#ffffff"
                android:text="The Language Lab focuses on the production and practice of sounds of language and familiarises the students with the use of English in everyday situations and contexts.   

Objectives
  To facilitate computer-aided multi-media instruction enabling individualized and independent language learning   
  To sensitise the students to the nuances of English speech sounds, word accent, intonation and rhythm  
  To bring about a consistent accent and intelligibility in their pronunciation of  English by providing an opportunity for practice in speaking 
  To improve the fluency in spoken English and neutralize mother tongue influence 
  To train students to use language appropriately for interviews, group discussion and public speaking  

Learning Outcomes: 
1. Better Understanding of nuances of language through audio- visual experience and group activities 
2. Neutralization of accent for intelligibility 
3. Speaking with clarity and confidence thereby enhancing employability skills of the students 

Syllabus:
 English Language Communication Skills Lab shall have two parts:
  a. Computer Assisted Language Learning (CALL) Lab 
  b. Interactive Communication Skills (ICS) Lab
    
The following course content is prescribed for the English Language Communication Skills Lab 
  
Exercise – I 
 CALL Lab: Introduction to Phonetics – Speech Sounds – Vowels and Consonants      ICS Lab: Ice-Breaking activity and JAM session Articles, Prepositions, Word formation- Prefixes and Suffixes, Synonyms and Antonyms  

Exercise – II 
CALL Lab: Structure of Syllables - Past Tense Marker and Plural Marker – Weak Forms and Strong Forms - Consonant Clusters.  ICS Lab: Situational Dialogues – Role-Play- Expressions in Various Situations – Self-introduction and Introducing Others – Greetings – Apologies – Requests – Social and Professional Etiquette - Telephone Etiquette. Concord (Subject in agreement with verb) and Words often misspelt- confused/misused  

Exercise - III
 CALL Lab: Minimal Pairs- Word accent and Stress Shifts- Listening Comprehension.  ICS Lab: Descriptions- Narrations- Giving Directions and guidelines.  Sequence of Tenses, Question Tags and One word substitutes.   

Exercise – IV 
CALL Lab: Intonation and Common errors in Pronunciation.  ICS Lab: Extempore- Public Speaking  Active and Passive Voice, –Common Errors in English, Idioms and Phrases  

Exercise – V 
CALL Lab: Neutralization of Mother Tongue Influence and Conversation Practice ICS Lab: Information Transfer- Oral Presentation Skills Reading Comprehension and Job Application with Resume preparation.   
                " />
            
             <TextView
                android:id="@+id/textView1"
                android:layout_width="wrap_content"
                android:layout_height="wrap_content"
                android:textColor="#ffffff"
                android:text="Minimum Requirement of infra structural facilities for ELCS Lab:
                 1. Computer Assisted Language Learning (CALL) Lab: 
                  The Computer aided Language Lab for 40 students with 40 systems, one master console, LAN facility and English language software for self- study by learners.    
                   
System Requirement (Hardware component):
 Computer network with Lan with minimum 60 multimedia systems with the following specifications: i) P – IV Processor a) Speed – 2.8 GHZ b) RAM – 512 MB Minimum c) Hard Disk – 80 GB ii) Headphones of High quality  

2. Interactive Communication Skills (ICS) Lab :  The Interactive Communication Skills Lab: A Spacious room with movable chairs and audio-visual aids with a Public Address System, a T. V., a digital stereo –audio and video system and camcorder etc.  


Books Suggested for English Language Lab Library (to be located within the lab in addition to the CDs of the text book which are loaded on the systems): 1. Suresh Kumar, E. and Sreehari, P. 2009. A Handbook for English Language Laboratories. New Delhi: Foundation 2. Strengthen Your Steps - Dr. M. Hari Prasad and others, Maruthi Publications 

3. Speaking English Effectively 2nd Edition by Krishna Mohan and N. P. Singh, 2011. Macmillan Publishers India Ltd. Delhi. 
4. Sasi Kumar, V and Dhamija, P.V. How to Prepare for Group Discussion and Interviews. Tata McGraw Hill 
5. Hancock, M. 2009. English Pronunciation in Use. Intermediate. Cambridge: CUP 
6. Spoken English: A Manual of Speech and Phonetics by R. K. Bansal and J. B. Harrison. 2013. Orient Blackswan. Hyderabad. 
7. Hewings, M. 2009. English Pronunciation in Use. Advanced. Cambridge: CUP 
8. Marks, J. 2009. English Pronunciation in Use. Elementary. Cambridge: CUP 
9. Nambiar, K.C. 2011. Speaking Accurately. A Course in International Communication. New Delhi : Foundation 
10. Soundararaj, Francis. 2012. Basics of Communication in English. New Delhi: Macmillan 
11. Spoken English (CIEFL) in 3 volumes with 6 cassettes, OUP. 
12. English Pronouncing Dictionary Daniel Jones Current Edition with CD. 
13. A textbook of English Phonetics for Indian Students by T. Balasubramanian (Macmillan) 
14. Lab Manual: A Manual entitled “English Language Communication Skills (ELCS) Lab Manual- cum- Work Book”, published by Cengage Learning India Pvt. Ltd, New Delhi. 2013  

DISTRIBUTION AND WEIGHTAGE OF MARKS English Language Laboratory Practical Examination: 
1. The practical examinations for the English Language Laboratory shall be conducted as per the University norms prescribed for the core engineering practical sessions. 
2. For the Language lab sessions, there shall be a continuous evaluation during the year for 25 sessional marks and 50 year-end Examination marks. Of the 25 marks, 15 marks shall be awarded for day-to-day work and 10 marks to be awarded by conducting Internal Lab Test(s). The year- end Examination shall be conducted by the teacher concerned with the help of another member of the staff of the same department of the same institution. " />

        </LinearLayout>
    </ScrollView>
    
</RelativeLayout>
<!-- From: file:/D:/Android/JntuHR13SyllabusBook/app/src/main/res/layout/activity_elcs_lab.xml -->